

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER · DEVELOPER ADVOCATE

🛮 (530) 356-7734 | 💌 joey.mckenzie27@gmail.com | 🎁 joeymckenzie.tech | 🖸 JoeyMcKenzie | 🛅 JoeyMcKenzie | 🗂 JoeyMcKenzie

Summary_

Seasoned developer with diverse experience building enterprise-grade distributed software systems primarily with technologies in .NET, Java and TypeScript in industries including healthcare, insurance, manufacturing, and fintech. I specialize in building fast, efficient web-based services and APIs, software architecture and design, software leadership and mentorship, and delivering high quality software products at nationwide scale.

I am an avid contributor to **open source** primarily in the **Rust** and **TypeScript** ecosystems alongside minor contributions in **Go**. I enjoy dispersing knowledge and experience with other like minded developers that share a similar passion for software development and design. I write and produce technical content available on my blog, Twitch, and YouTube exploring emerging technologies with a focus on developer relations.

Experience_

National Funding Remote

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2022 - Present

- Developing .NET microservices, React applications with Next.js, and AWS infrastructure supporting financial operations
- Integrating external financial partner APIs into backend systems, increasing customer lending conversion by up to 50%
- Managing CI/CD pipelines and automated processes with AWS, Terraform, Jenkins, and containerized workflows with Docker
- Upgrading internal .NET infrastructure improving performance and speed by 30% while reducing AWS costs
- Troubleshooting applications errors using log aggregation services with OpenSearch and Kibana
- Led company-wide modernization efforts to develop publicly available APIs for consumers in the fintech space

MediKeeper Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec. 2020 - Jan. 2022

- Developed .NET and JavaScript applications with Vue deployed to Azure infrastructure
- Iterated on **UX** with product designers to increase user retention and impression conversion rates
- Created CI/CD pipelines and automated processes with Azure DevOps to improve existing build times
- · Administered SQL Server and Oracle databases while improving business critical query times by up to 60%
- Improved existing system architecture by migrating legacy .NET Framework applications to modern .NET
- Maintained integration suites with JavaScript and Cypress to automate platform testing, increasing QA velocity by 20%

Sierra Pacific Industries Redding, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- · Developed internal applications and dashboards using modern RPG ILE on the IBM iSeries AS/400 and .NET for desktop applications
- · Migrated brownfield and legacy applications to modern RPG architectures increasing application response times
- Improved business critical **PL/SQL** queries for **embedded systems** by up to 40% in several applications
- · Administered system tasks on the IBM iSeries AS/400 to maintain environmental integrity increase system up-time
- Managed database schemas with **SQL Server** using **SSMS** to support inventory management operations

VSP Global Sacramento, CA

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun. 2018 - Jan. 2020

- Developed **Java** APIs and **Angular** applications with **TypeScript** for nationwide use by optometry offices and retailers
- Migrated **JEE** and **Spring** applications to **Spring Boot** while increasing response times by up to 25%
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Lead development of } \textbf{Angular} \ \text{applications utilizing } \textbf{Angular Material}, \textbf{SCSS}, \textbf{NgRx}, \text{and modern web standards}$
- Created and maintained CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins deployed to AWS hosting infrastructure
- · Administrated systems and servers while migrating non-production workloads off legacy Windows servers to Linux servers
- · Assisted in troubleshooting company-wide service outages and application performance issues with Splunk and Wily

Engility Corporation San Diego, CA

Operations Research Analyst

- Wrote and maintained **VBA** and **R** codebases to perform data analysis and spreadsheet specific functionality
- · Provided contractor support for U.S. Department of Defense naval programs for systems engineering and data analysis
- Performed regression analysis and statistical programming using R to refine estimated financial expenditure models
- Managed automated Excel spreadsheets and codebases in RStudio for data analysis and exploration
- Maintained databases of financial data and provided ad hoc SQL reporting for various projects

Education

San Diego State University

San Diego, CA

Sept. 2016 - May. 2018

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ASTROPHYSICS, MINOR IN MATHEMATICS

May 2016

Coursework included training in: scientific computation, procedural and object-oriented programming, advanced mathematics, physics, astronomy, data structures, and numerical algorithms with thesis on computational photometry for stellar astrophysics